[{"id": "6015eaccfe83fe1f2a824bf5", "question": "What does the color blue represent in the American flag?", "answer": "Blue symbolizes vigilance, perseverance and justice.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b695", "question": "What color is the legendary Hope Diamond?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b48e649076251badbeaa8", "question": "Who was the first American woman in space?", "answer": "Sally Ride -- One of six women selected for NASA Astronaut Group 8, she traveled on Space Shuttle Challenger's STS-7 mission.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff08fd2e662d71a53650fb2", "question": "Which philosophical movement helped inspire the American Revolution?", "answer": "The Enlightenment -- It included great leaps in philosophical thought \u2014 including ideas about democracy, the social contract, and freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affc", "question": "What phrase first appeared on the American 2 cent coinin 1864?", "answer": "In God We Trust", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad4", "question": "In 2004, what golfer ended Tiger Woods' reign as the number 1 men's player in the world?", "answer": "Vijay Singh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ebb408d98002fdd633b1", "question": "When was the maiden voyage of the \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958c", "question": "What song did Wayne and Garth listen to on their way to the doughnut shop in the movie \"Wayne's World\"?", "answer": "Bohemian Rhapsody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e9", "question": "What was the name of the law firm featured in the TV series \"The Practice\"?", "answer": "Robert Donnell and Associates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c398", "question": "The \"Standard Model\" theory applies to which branch of science?", "answer": "Physics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fcc1b64c97eb73f6a51a271", "question": "Who said, \"Love the life you live. Live the life you love\"?", "answer": "Bob Marley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca8", "question": "Who kicked last-second field goals to win two different Super Bowls?", "answer": "Adam Vinateri", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfbd49dc5ec6cd98a8318", "question": "Who painted \"The Starry Night\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a959", "question": "Which European country replaced the Schilling with the Euro?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0afa8e662d71a53650fc2", "question": "Who is \"the Lord\" referred to in the title \"Lord of the Rings\"?", "answer": "Sauron", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3d", "question": "What were the first modern Olympic pole vaulters' poles made of?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d3", "question": "The card game Patience is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Solitaire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0e", "question": "Whose print of a banana is the cover of the 1967 album \"The Velvet Underground and Nico\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25b", "question": "Which amendment to the US Constitution deals with abolishing slavery?", "answer": "Thirteenth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6016015dfe83fe1f2a824c5e", "question": "Traditional May Day celebrations in Germany and surrounding nations was tied-in with the recognition of which saint?", "answer": "Saint Walpurgis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01a", "question": "Ranger VII was the first US spacecraft to send back pictures of what?", "answer": "The moon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c103", "question": "What is a kookaburra?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601219ec63c99d48cd169afd", "question": "Who is the oldest man to win People Magazine\u2019s sexiest man alive?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ea", "question": "Which US president lived in Ash Lawn-Highland?", "answer": "James Monroe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72b", "question": "The Ohio River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a296", "question": "Billy Joel's \"Uptown Girl\" music video featured which supermodel?", "answer": "Christie Brinkley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25146b63e5727cf5a4838", "question": "What place does Argentina take on the list of the World\u2019s largest countries by land area?", "answer": "Eighth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f55", "question": "What is the name of Woody's horse in the movie franchise \"Toy Story\"?", "answer": "Bullseye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef62e06ce05a3942286e60", "question": "What was HBO originally called?", "answer": "The Green Channel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc3536ce05a3942286f22", "question": "What is the name of Jack Nicholson's character in the film, \"Chinatown\"?", "answer": "J.J \"Jake\" Gittes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3586ff048f679a45ab03", "question": "A single piece of coiled DNA is known as what?", "answer": "Chromosome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab57", "question": "Which former Soviet Republic in Central Asia has Tashkent as its capital?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590720d03745b36be73039f3", "question": "What year did Disney release a 3D motion-capture adaptation of \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "2009", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339799", "question": "Glen Frey and Don Henley were members of which band?", "answer": "Eagles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e918b24f84e0b9f9ffc9", "question": "What year did Botswana gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1966", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962b", "question": "In what movie does Nicole Kidman play a ghost?", "answer": "The Others", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b332", "question": "Which country hosted the Olympic Games In 2004?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389aa", "question": "What novel by Louisa May Alcott tells about the lives and loves of four sisters?", "answer": "Little Women", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a9", "question": "Which US state shares a border with the Yukon territory?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6018bb6ad96d05b23b28164e", "question": "In addition to the main Passover, there is also a second one called the Second Passover. When is the Second Passover celebrated?", "answer": "The Second Paassover (also called \"Pesach Sheni\") is observed on the 14th day of the Hebrew Calendar month of Iyar.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa3c773838c5c8a417f21", "question": "In 1612, who became the first person to observe Neptune?", "answer": "Galileo Galilei - However, he thought he was observing a star and not a planet.  Therefore, he did not receive credit for discovering the planet.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d01", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"1984\"?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984a", "question": "Who played Chad Gates in the 1961 movie \"Blue Hawaii\"?", "answer": "Elvis Presley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989ac8ecb8751d53e7d760b", "question": "When was the polka dot jersey first awarded at the Tour de France to the \"King of the Mountains\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98e", "question": "In what year did England win its first FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "1966", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b522", "question": "What popular operating system are the Mac OS X series based on?", "answer": "Unix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957d", "question": "The movie \"Best in Show\" was a mockumentary that examined a fictional what?", "answer": "Dog show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab14a5baab681b09292177", "question": "What year did GM first introduce the Corvette?", "answer": "1953", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56f", "question": "Which Australian animal has unique fingerprints?", "answer": "Koala", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f1936682715b82711ce2", "question": "The fear of fire is known as what?", "answer": "Pyrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca24", "question": "How many kilograms make up a metric tonne?", "answer": "1000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c60", "question": "What liqueur was Vincent Van Gogh said to be heavily drinking heavily the night he cut off his ear?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca5", "question": "Who wrote the science-fiction novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f544ff048f679a45aad4", "question": "Ombrophobia fear of what?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a996e61d1b4d384d5d69a", "question": "What TV network was home to the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "CBS", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a15b20565ad31a57c7a2", "question": "What country used camouflage specialists in the army for the first time?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a23", "question": "What was the name of Oliver Douglas' wife on the TV show \"Green Acres\"?", "answer": "Lisa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7df", "question": "What US city was the first Starbucks store opened in?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff66f4952a821ff76ae8b1e", "question": "In Skamania County, Washington, it\u2019s illegal to kill what creature?", "answer": "Bigfoot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bc25d96d05b23b281653", "question": "\"An eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth\" is a well-known phrase from what collection of 282 laws?", "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe1f17b145fb29466707393", "question": "What does the Italian term \"Al Dente\" mean in regards to pasta?", "answer": "To the teeth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923b", "question": "What is the nickname of Andy's prison buddy in \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c625fbde8045e48466b4", "question": "What is the longest-lived vertebrate animal?", "answer": "Outlasting all other vertebrates, Greenland sharks have been found to reach at least 272 years of age, and possibly 512 years old.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febaa667e83c707845b20df", "question": "Which colors are at the extreme ends of the visible color spectrum?", "answer": "Red and violet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a63", "question": "What Shakespeare work includes the line \"Friends, Romans, countrymen, lend me your ears\"?", "answer": "Julius Caesar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c280", "question": "What abbreviation comes from libra, meaning pound in Latin?", "answer": "lb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25d", "question": "Which amendment to the US Constitution deals with presidential succession?", "answer": "Twenty fifth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d37", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Jed Clampett\"?", "answer": "Flatt and Scruggs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a6", "question": "In what European city is the house located where Anne Frank and her family hid from the Nazis?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a95", "question": "In ancient Greece, what river did the souls of dead people have to cross?", "answer": "Styx", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c8bbfbde8045e48466df", "question": "Around 280 million years ago, the continents existed as one landmass called what?", "answer": "Pangea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339589", "question": "What movie includes the quote \"Your heart is free. Have the courage to follow it\"?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae950e574a5ce6b56b8250", "question": "What is the capital of Malawi?", "answer": "Lilongwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ba", "question": "Which is the world's northernmost capital city?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be581a05415ba52ed6f0ac3", "question": "Who released an autobiography titled \"Making Waves: The Autobiography\"?", "answer": "David Hasselhoff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d115da4fea7fe947a2226a", "question": "Ernest Evans became famous under what name?", "answer": "Chubby Checker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390bb", "question": "Which English author created Inspector Morse?", "answer": "Colin Dexter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbfb06ce05a3942286f03", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Some Guys Have All the Luck\"?", "answer": "Rod Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339efd", "question": "What 1977 hit was the theme of Bill Clinton's 1992 presidential campaign?", "answer": "Don't Stop by Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f8", "question": "What was the subtitle of the 2005 movie \"Miss Congeniality 2\"?", "answer": "Armed and Fabulous", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a065", "question": "According to the song what did my true love give to me on the fifth day of Christmas?", "answer": "Five gold rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a963", "question": "What split up into Gondwanaland and Laurasia?", "answer": "Pangaea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c118", "question": "Sapporo beer was first brewed in which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e12", "question": "What two \"Brokeback Mountain\" actors have siblings who are also award-winning actors?", "answer": "Jake Gyllenhaal and Randy Quaid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ec7908d98002fdd633bc", "question": "Who played the character of Rose in the 1953 film \"Niagara\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8b8bec223966ae8f883f", "question": "Who does the voice over for Dory from \"Finding Nemo\" and \"Finding Dory\"?", "answer": "Ellen DeGeneres", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66bdba5bfecdd737e088a", "question": "What is the only bird to have its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c9", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Pinocchio?", "answer": "1883", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7a", "question": "What umbrella term is used to describe a painful stiffness of the muscles and joints?", "answer": "Rheumatism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf5", "question": "The candy PEZ was first sold in which country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b370281c3f17ccc40c8e11", "question": "What is \"pub\" short for?", "answer": "Public House", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3da", "question": "What year did poet Sylvia Plath die?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b918e662d71a5365102c", "question": "\"The Color Purple\" begins, \"You better not tell nobody but\" who?", "answer": "God", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c507", "question": "What sensory organ do starfish have at the end of each arm?", "answer": "Eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befb", "question": "What New York Giants' bone-crushing tackle in 1985 ended quarterback Joe Thiemann's career?", "answer": "Lawrence Taylor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe699cf20565ad31a57c74b", "question": "What was the U.S. Hush Hush in World War II?", "answer": "Admiral Nimitz's Jeep", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e1", "question": "Who directed the classic horror film \"The Birds\"?", "answer": "Alfred Hitchcock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d4d22b42d4a3561a9efc", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", which employee of Mrs. Parker was framed with stealing $850,000 from Senator Chalmers?", "answer": "Samantha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdb69ec223966ae8f88f5", "question": "The script for what movie was written during shooting breaks on the set of \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "E.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1b", "question": "Who employs Alfred Pennyworth as a butler?", "answer": "Bruce Wayne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fad", "question": "In ballet, a lowering of the body by bending the knee is called a what?", "answer": "Fondu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937eeec08d98002fdd633db", "question": "What is 2000 in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "MM", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b474", "question": "What year did Andre and Edouard Michelin first publish the \"Michelin Guide\"?", "answer": "1900", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a98", "question": "What directions does Peter Pan give to Neverland?", "answer": "Second to the right, and then straight on till morning", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59774470284458f1d7854430", "question": "What American discount retail chain is headquartered in Bentonville, Arkansas?", "answer": "Walmart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4de1406d333868d34d70e", "question": "Mustafa Kemal was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cefc0d8948005ec986edce0", "question": "Who is the seventh member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Jinsoul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c5e9fbde8045e48466b2", "question": "A \"smack\" is one of the seven names for a group of what aquatic animal?", "answer": "Jellyfish -- The other six acceptable names include bloom, swarm, brood, fluther, smuth, and stuck.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c62b86e0ae4aacefc17eee1", "question": "What was Studio Ghibli's highest grossing film?", "answer": "Spirited Away", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75d", "question": "What was the name of Underdog's girlfriend?", "answer": "Polly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7c0fa2b316f4693fb679a", "question": "What is a duel between three people called?", "answer": "Truel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f2", "question": "A Sone is a unit of what?", "answer": "Loudness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe25717658e585fda9cfa3a", "question": "What destructive party item was banned in Hollywood on Halloween starting in 2004?", "answer": "Silly String", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf5", "question": "What's the name of the Jolly Green Giant's sidekick?", "answer": "Little Green Sprout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7a", "question": "What Italian phrase for \"from the beginning\" is used in music notation to indicate a repeated passage?", "answer": "Da capo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae53", "question": "What was the name given to the first German democracy established in 1919?", "answer": "Weimar Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3e3244f0f6af5b066647", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 21?", "answer": "Zepto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8a9a801dd7bf43be5e751", "question": "What did the \"Itsy Bitsy Spider\" climb up?", "answer": "Water spout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32368ebf195a31e15d73bc", "question": "An \"omniscient\" person has unlimited what?", "answer": "Knowledge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ae", "question": "The first spin-off of C.S.I., starting in 2002, was set in what city?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c2", "question": "Who played the role of Frank Rossitano on the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "Judah Friedlander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37af80ada16518afdc05e", "question": "What action did the U.S. take along with Great Britain and Australia after Japan seized Indochina?", "answer": "They formed a trade embargo that cut off 90% of Japan's oil supply", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da6", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Snout?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c802", "question": "What are male honeybees called?", "answer": "Drones", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54c", "question": "\"Consumption\" was the former name of what disease?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c0", "question": "As what type of beans are chickpeas also known as?", "answer": "Garbanzo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d4aa2596a59cbdfbd3a6", "question": "What does bone marrow produce?", "answer": "Red and white blood cells, as well as platelets.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2157531a458464a93c45f", "question": "What is the name given to people who make arrows?", "answer": "Fletcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de6", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"orangutan\"?", "answer": "Malay", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062ba7c9d816e292245c22", "question": "What is the name of Captain Ahab's ship?", "answer": "The Pequod", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339220", "question": "Who were the principal members of the band \"The Beatles\"?", "answer": "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1fd", "question": "In what city did the First and Second Continental Congresses meet?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96e5b23c87fd04dd15e36", "question": "Which U.S. president owned a pet hyena?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d1", "question": "In which film did Kevin Costner make his directorial debut?", "answer": "Dances with Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e0c7fe83fe1f2a824b91", "question": "What were the first two Western countries that the Nazis invaded during World War II?", "answer": "Norway and Denmark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c250", "question": "What do you call an animal that eats both plants and animals?", "answer": "An Omnivore", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3b", "question": "How many players are there in a standard polo team?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c1", "question": "When was Indira Gandhi assassinated?", "answer": "October 31, 1984", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071ec93745b36be73039e5", "question": "In the \"Revival\" comic book series, what is the family name of the brothers who try to sell parts of the revivers?", "answer": "Check", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6003988f57a0e35c43f8389c", "question": "What female surrealist did Andre Breton call \"the sorceress who left too soon\"?", "answer": "Male surrealists almost never saw female painters as capable artists.  Varo proved them wrong with her images of women.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51f", "question": "What are the four largest islands of Japan?", "answer": "Honshu, Kyushu, Shikoku, Hokkaido", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c4", "question": "What is the technical term for egg white?", "answer": "Albumen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac17", "question": "Victoria is the capital of which country and archipelago located northeast of Madagascar?", "answer": "Seychelles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f565ef33a95c66dc4fe75c", "question": "Bismarck is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339195", "question": "What was the first CD ever pressed in the US?", "answer": "Bruce Springsteen's Born in the USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a3", "question": "Who wrote the novel on which the movie, by the same name, \"Jurassic Park\" is based on?", "answer": "Michael Crichton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd59", "question": "The Vezina Trophy is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Hockey goaltending", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3bf744f0f6af5b06662a", "question": "What Canadian professional snooker player is nicknamed \"Champagne Cliff\"?", "answer": "Cliff Thorburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323599bf195a31e15d73b0", "question": "Who were defeated by the New York Mets in the 1969 World Series?", "answer": "The Orioles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3234babf195a31e15d73a8", "question": "Which chemical element gets its name from the Greek for \"Violet-colored\"?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133972f", "question": "What does Popeye have tattooed on his arm?", "answer": "An anchor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339414", "question": "\"Hello, Clara?\" is the last line from what Oscar-winning film?", "answer": "Marty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a150", "question": "What did Dorothy's house land on in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "The Wicked Witch of the East", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a4", "question": "Which US state was established by William Penn in 1681?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8893ec223966ae8f8820", "question": "Which singer began her rise to superstardom actually as a dancer on a sketch-comedy television program?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez (she was a dancer on the Wayans Brothers' TV Show \"In Living Color\")", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d95", "question": "What TV character had great success with his recipe for Chocolate Salty Balls?", "answer": "Chef", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab94f486faa38a764be511", "question": "In the automotive world, what does the abbreviation DOHC mean?", "answer": "Dual OverHead Cam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9bbc5364247bf200fb8a7", "question": "Lusaka is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e6", "question": "What is the official name of the Michelin Man?", "answer": "Bibendum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900e", "question": "What was Tom Clancy's blockbuster first novel, published in 1984?", "answer": "The Hunt for Red October", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b76", "question": "Whose novels include \"The Chamber\", \"The Client\", and \"The Firm\"?", "answer": "John Grisham", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ce", "question": "Who wrote \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Neil Gaiman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a515", "question": "Africa's Victoria Falls are on which river?", "answer": "Zambezi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c344", "question": "What are you afraid of if you have \"chionophobia\"?", "answer": "Snow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b898", "question": "What four colors traditionally correspond with first through fourth place ribbons?", "answer": "Blue, Red, White, Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c90d3ff52800b05cac20f1a", "question": "What is the real name of the DC character Deathstroke?", "answer": "Slade Wilson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c466", "question": "Which bodily organ produces urine?", "answer": "The kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b1744b5bb2d29f81593b6fc", "question": "In the 1986 movie \"Aliens\", what was Newt's real name?", "answer": "Rebecca Jorden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14f", "question": "What is the fear of the color purple called?", "answer": "Porphyrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b79c", "question": "What color is the central square on a Scrabble board?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b039", "question": "What former US President died one week before the 1973 cease fire in Vietnam?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590498b2cf93664eb104868a", "question": "A statue of Lady Godiva stands in the centre which English city?", "answer": "Coventry", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339739", "question": "Which artist was born Artis Leon Ivey Jr.?", "answer": "Coolio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3cb4c73aa70ea0b70aee", "question": "Which capital name means \"City of Joy?\"", "answer": "Bucharest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c74a877e98cb977789ca", "question": "Which US state capital features a full-scale replica of the Parthenon?", "answer": "Nashville", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabe", "question": "On the Mohs scale, what is the softest mineral?", "answer": "Talc", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8aca001dd7bf43be5e76f", "question": "The pavlova dessert is named after a professional in what artistic field?", "answer": "Ballet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ca", "question": "In what US state was Abraham Lincoln born?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e1f1fe83fe1f2a824b9a", "question": "After changing sides during World War II, what was Italy's primary objective?", "answer": "It distracted Germany from accomplishing its main objectives", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600782aebd51d85e222ab659", "question": "Who claimed he could \"drive away the devil with a fart\"?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133947d", "question": "Which actress won an Oscar for her performance in the 1998 movie \"Shakespeare in Love\"?", "answer": "Gwyneth Paltrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396fe", "question": "Ringo Star narrated the original episodes of which children's TV series?", "answer": "Thomas the Tank Engine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab99", "question": "Which US state shares a nickname with the Australian state of Queensland?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339641", "question": "What is the name of Thor's hammer?", "answer": "Mjolnir", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70d48f96e155acab35d32", "question": "What is the most densely populated US state?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfff", "question": "Who is known as \"Big Mama\" in ladies pro golf?", "answer": "JoAnne Carner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdd29ec223966ae8f8900", "question": "What band is the film \"Bohemian Rhapsody\" about?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da1", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Hagen?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f507ff048f679a45aad0", "question": "Necrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Death and dead things", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5a", "question": "What president delivered his \"Fourteen Points\" speech in Congress in 1918?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdab5750b8cce1e6fda704d", "question": "According to the jingle, which coffee brand is the best part of waking up?", "answer": "Folgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e93a27ccba3ffe45786c8", "question": "The \"miner's lamp\" is also known as what?", "answer": "Davy's Lamp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071cb03745b36be73039cf", "question": "In what present-day country was the first space launch facility located?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47b", "question": "When did the Battle of the Plains of Abraham take place?", "answer": "1759", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe699b720565ad31a57c74a", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7b", "question": "In what Tom Cruise movie does his character play a doctor?", "answer": "Eyes Wide Shut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339111", "question": "What boxer appeared in the broadway musical \"Buck White\" in 1969?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abae", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Maryland?", "answer": "Annapolis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133952a", "question": "What is the name of Simba's uncle in the movie \"The Lion King\"?", "answer": "Scar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c9", "question": "What state is nicknamed the \"Beehive State\"?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a459", "question": "The Bermuda Triangle is located in what ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab79", "question": "What large African island nation is located just west of Mauritius?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a50e", "question": "Which river helped create the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a658", "question": "What historic theater district is located in New York?", "answer": "Broadway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c050", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Egypt?", "answer": "Golden eagle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d1", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Cump\"?", "answer": "William Tecumseh Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d5", "question": "What shoulder should you throw spilled salt over?", "answer": "The left", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0a", "question": "In 1997, what Oscar winner was replaced by Sarah Ferguson as Weight Watchers' spokesperson?", "answer": "Lynn Redgrave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa55273838c5c8a417f23", "question": "Who discovered the life or death importance of washing hands while studying maternity wards?", "answer": "Ignaz Philipp Semmelweis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b392", "question": "In what country did the \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339874", "question": "In Disney's \"The Jungle Book\", what is King Louie's greatest desire?", "answer": "To obtain fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bbff364247bf200fb8ac", "question": "From which plant do we get linseed oil?", "answer": "Flax", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc4", "question": "Who was the first American in space?", "answer": "Alan Shepard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc37f6de0eb824d4052ed", "question": "What U.S. state is the smallest by land area?", "answer": "Rhode Island -- At 1214 sq.mi., it is half the size of Miami-Dade County, FL (2431 sq. mi), but has nearly 400 miles of shoreline.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fc", "question": "According to Toucan Sam, what should you always follow to find Froot Loops?", "answer": "Your nose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523c45736d4be723796b36", "question": "What is the name of the highway that travels through all ten Canadian provinces?", "answer": "Trans-Canada Highway, or Route Transcanadienne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac19", "question": "When did the Comoros gain its independence from France?", "answer": "July 6, 1975", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d06ee1a1c922dd1ac64b2", "question": "Where would you find the Pont Neuf bridge?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ec238b8dc25ca9e12ef631", "question": "What nationality was Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Chopin?", "answer": "Polish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b060", "question": "When did the Panama Canal open?", "answer": "1914", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77e", "question": "What is the hardest known naturally occurring mineral?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fce", "question": "Where did Aristotle believe the seat of intelligence was?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bfdff85b668d7dfe168b5b9", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Jason's great-grandfather?", "answer": "Hermes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37b", "question": "Which English sci-fi writer first conceived the idea of artificial communication satellites in 1945?", "answer": "Arthur C. Clarke", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bd50877e98cb97778959", "question": "What continent is located at Latitude 90\u00b0 S Longitude 0.00\u00b0 E?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e93567ccba3ffe45786c5", "question": "What word is used to describe \"bell shaped flowers\"?", "answer": "Campanulate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede4946ce05a3942286dde", "question": "Which American tennis player popularized metal rackets by first using a Wilson T2000?", "answer": "Jimmy Connors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b287", "question": "Molotov cocktails were first used by what country after the Soviets invaded it in 1939?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121cc563c99d48cd169b18", "question": "What is the real name of Chicago\u2019s \"The Bean\"?", "answer": "\"Cloud Gate\", by artist Sir Anish Kapoor, gives a perfect view of the Chicago skyline in its reflective stainless steel surface.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae78", "question": "In 2010, the Deepwater Horizon oil spill polluted the waters of what body of water?", "answer": "Gulf of Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb3216e368446ca7bd6840", "question": "Which element has the lowest boiling point?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6d", "question": "What are you frightened of if you are Alektorophobic?", "answer": "Chickens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d80", "question": "What ABC TV star is the great-grandson of a billionaire oilman?", "answer": "Balthazar Getty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a111", "question": "What does the \"E\" stand for in Wile E. Coyote's name?", "answer": "Ethelbert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a5", "question": "What car lost 96 percent of its sales in the four years after the publication of Ralph Nader's \"Unsafe at Any Speed\"?", "answer": "Chevrolet Corvair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ef", "question": "Who was appointed the first leader of the Tuskegee Institute in 1881?", "answer": "Booker T. Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9096c01dd7bf43be5e88f", "question": "Aphyllous trees lack what?", "answer": "Leaves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b98", "question": "What legendary San Francisco rock band, that formed in 1965, was originally known as \"The Warlocks\"?", "answer": "The Grateful Dead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc6", "question": "What was the name of the ship that Jason & his Argonauts sail in?", "answer": "Argo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11f", "question": "Somniphobia is a fear of what?", "answer": "Sleep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000edf09a72b906b34e3cf2", "question": "What is the name of the largest vein in the human body?", "answer": "The inferior vena cava", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b174555bb2d29f81593b700", "question": "Lou Gramm was a member of which British-American rock band?", "answer": "Foreigner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a6", "question": "Which country were the 1932 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United States", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b996", "question": "In 1982, who began selling spaghetti sauce, turning over all profits to charity?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d2", "question": "How does James Bond like his martinis?", "answer": "Shaken", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ee", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of the studio where Krusty's show is taped?", "answer": "Krustylu Studios", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978d", "question": "What 1978 movie inspired toga parties on college campuses?", "answer": "Animal House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3701ff048f679a45ab12", "question": "Which Austrian psychiatrist penned \"The Interpretation of Dreams\" in 1900?", "answer": "Sigmund Freud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7dd", "question": "What Asian dog breed is notable for its blue or black tongue?", "answer": "The Chow Chow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca42", "question": "Which vital organ does the adjective renal refer to?\u00a0", "answer": "Kidney\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1eb", "question": "Who released the album titled \"The Spaghetti Incident\"?", "answer": "Guns N' Roses", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59220089a4edfd43a087add8", "question": "What was the name of Henry VIII's ship that was raised from the Solent in 1982?", "answer": "Mary Rose", "category": "history"}]